A stiff drink. A little mascara. A lot of nerve. Who said
they couldn't bring down the Soviet empire.
Charlie Wilson's War is a comedy, drama, history film directed by Mike Nichols.
A Texas congressman sets a series of events in motion when he conspires with a CIA
operative to aid Afghan mujahideen rebels fighting the Soviets.
Charlie Wilson, played by Tom Hanks.
Joanne Herring, played by Julia Roberts.
Gust Avrakotos, played by Philip Seymour Hoffman.
Bonnie Bach, played by Amy Adams.
Jane Liddle, played by Emily Blunt.
President Zia, played by Om Puri.
Charlie Wilson's War is a 2007 American biographical
comedy-drama film based on the story of U.S.
Congressman Charlie Wilson and CIA operative Gust Avrakotos, whose efforts led to Operation Cyclone, a
program to organize and support the Afghan mujahideen during the Soviet–Afghan War (1979–89).
The film was directed by Mike Nichols (his final film) and written by Aaron Sorkin, who adapted George Crile III's
2003 book Charlie Wilson's War: The Extraordinary Story of the Largest Covert Operation in History.
It stars Tom Hanks, Julia Roberts, and Philip Seymour Hoffman,
with Amy Adams and Ned Beatty in supporting roles.
It was released by Universal Pictures on December 21, 2007 and received generally positive reviews, with praise
for the performances (particularly Hoffman's), and grossed $119.5 million on a $75 million budget.
It earned five nominations at the 65th Golden Globe Awards, including Best Motion Picture – Musical or
Comedy, and Hoffman earned a Best Supporting Actor nomination at the 80th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of central intelligence agency (cia),
helicopter, washington dc, usa, congress, cairo.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.